爱是一首永不止息的诗歌
Love is a song that never ends
生命也许变幻无常
Life may be swift and fleeting
希望也许会破灭，但是爱的美妙乐章
Hope may die Yet love's beautiful music
就像黎明般清新恒常
Comes each day like the dawn
爱是一首永不止息的诗歌
Love is a song that never ends
一个简单的主题不停回响
One simple theme repeating
就像是天堂传来的歌声
Like the voice of a heavenly choir
爱的美妙乐章永远流传
Love's sweet music flows on
就像是天堂传来的歌声
Like the voice of a heavenly choir
爱的美妙乐章永远流传
Love's sweet music flows on
起床！起床！
Wake up.
又怎么了啊？
What now?
快点起床喔！猫头鹰
Wake up, Friend Owl.
到底发生什么事？
What's going on around here?
- 起床啦！  - 有大事发生了！
-Wake up. -It's happened.
新的王子诞生了！
The new prince is born.
我们要去看它哟！
We're going to see him.
对！要看就快点哟！
Come on. You better hurry up.
看啊
Well, look.
好可爱哟！
-Well. -Isn't he cute?
真难得的场面，太热闹了
Well, this is quite an occasion.
当然了，这也难怪了 不是每天都有王子出生的
Yes, sir, it isn't every day a prince is born.
你们应该好好的道贺一下
You're to be congratulated.
对呀…恭喜呀…
-Yes, congratulations. -Congratulations.
谢谢你们，赶快醒来吧！
Thank you very much. Come on.
我们有客人来了！
Wake up. We have company.
你好啊，小可爱！
Hello. Hello, there.
你好啊，小王子！
Hello, little prince.
你好啊，小王子！！
你们看，它想要站起来了
Look. He's trying to get up.
它还是站得摇摇晃晃的
Kinda wobbly, isn't he?
桑普！
Thumper.
我说的没错啊
Well, he is.
你说是不是？
Aren't you?
我看它是有点困了 让它好好休息
Looks to me like he's getting kind of sleepy.
好了，我们该走了
I think it's time we all left.
走吧
Come on.
快走啊！
桑普，该走了！
Thumper. Come on.
你要给它取什么名字啊？
Whatcha gonna call him?
这个嘛… 我想就叫它 “斑比” 好了
Well, I think I'll call him Bambi.
斑比…
Bambi.
可以，这个名字不错
Yep, I guess that'll do all right.
斑比…
Bambi.
我的小斑比
My little Bambi.
它已经会走路了
Walking already.
你看谁来了？
Well, what do you know.
早安！
Good morning.
早安啊，鹌鹑太太！
Good morning, Mrs Quail.
早上怎么不见到小王子呢？
And where's the young prince this...
早安啊，斑比！
Good morning, Bambi.
早安，小王子…
Good morning, young prince.
再见！
Goodbye.
早安啊，小王子！
Good morning, young prince.
早安，小王子！
早安！
Good morning.
今天天气不错哟！
Nice sunny day.
- 怎么了  - 发生什么事情了 ？
-What's the matter? -What happened?
小王子跌倒了吗？
Did the young prince fall down?
它受伤了吗？
Is he hurt?
没有，它很好啊！
No, he's all right.
它走路像不大稳
He doesn't walk very good, does he?
桑普！
Thumper.
什么事，妈妈？
Yes, Mama?
你爸爸今天早上 是怎么跟你说的
What did your father tell you this morning?
假如你不能说好听的话
If you can't say something nice,
那就…一句…一句也都不要说
don't say nothing at all.
斑比，要勇敢喔！
Come on, Bambi, get up. Try again.
赶快起来，站起来喔！
Come on, get up.
对呀，起来嘛！斑比！
Come on, get up.get up.
来试试看嘛！
Try again.
我很会敲打
I'm thumping.
所以呢…大家都叫我桑普喔！
That's why they call me Thumper.
桑普！
Thumper!
跳过来呀！你可以跳得过来的
Come on. You can do it.
快点嘛，像这样子喔！
Hop over it. Like this.
我表演给你看喔！
Hop over it.
就像这样！
Like this.
你跳的还不够远喔！
You didn't hop far enough.
对了，现在换另外一只脚
That's it. Now the other one.
天啊！刚才是怎么一回事啊？
Gee whiz, what happened that time?
那是一群小鸟喔！
Those are birds.
鸟？
Bird.
鸟！
它是在学说话
Look, he's trying to talk.
鸟！
Bird.
它是在说：鸟！
He's trying to say "bird."
说 “鸟”
Say "bird."
鸟！
Bird.
鸟
鸟！
Bird.
不对！不对！是 “鸟”
快点说鸟嘛！快说啊！
Come on, say "bird," say "bird."
Say "bird." Say "bird." Come on, say "bird."
快点说鸟嘛！
Say "bird."
鸟！
Bird.
它说话了！它说话了…
He talked. He talked, Mama.
小王子说话了
The young prince said "bird."
鸟…鸟
Bird, bird, bird...
鸟！
Bird.
不对喔，那只不是鸟
No, that's not a bird.
那只是蝴蝶
That's a butterfly.
蝴蝶？
Butterfly?
蝴...
Butter...
蝴蝶！
Butterfly.
不对，那是花！
No, that's a flower.
花？
Flower?
是漂亮的花
It's pretty.
漂亮！
Pretty.
花！
Flower.
说我吗？
Me?
笑死我了
No, no, no, no.
不是啦，你说错了
That's not a flower.
那只不是花，它是…
He's a little...
没关系！
That's all right.
它喜欢叫我花，那就叫好了
He can call me a flower if he wants to.
我不会在乎的
I don't mind.
漂亮！
Pretty.
漂亮的花
Pretty flower.
你真的说我…
Gosh.
我想我现在该回家了
I think I better go home now.
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
一滴一滴  奏出美妙的旋律
Beating a tune As you fall all around
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
奏出世上最美妙的旋律
What can compare With your beautiful sound?
美妙的旋律  美妙的旋律
Beautiful sound Beautiful sound
滴滴答答  滴滴答答
Drip, drop Drip, drop
滴滴答答  当天空乌云密布
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你的美妙旋律让人心情开朗
Your pretty music Can brighten the day
滴滴答答  当天空乌云密布
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你就唱出一首动听的歌
You come along with a song right away
唱出美妙的旋律
Come with your beautiful music
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
一滴一滴  奏出美妙的旋律
Beating a tune As you fall all around
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
奏出世上最美妙的旋律
What can compare With your beautiful sound?
滴滴答答  当天空乌云密布
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你就唱出一首动听的歌
You come along With your pretty little song
滴滴答答  当天空乌云密布
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你就唱出一首动听的歌
You come along With your pretty little song
快乐的小老鼠  快乐的小老鼠
-Gay little roundelay -Gay little roundelay
下雨天的歌谣  下雨天的歌谣
-Song of the rainy day -Song of the rainy day
我好爱听那悠扬的雨滴声
How I love to hear your patter Pretty little pitter-patter
当你全身淋湿 所有的烦恼都会消失
Helter skelter, when you pelter Troubles always seem to scatter
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
下得到处都是
Beating a sound as you fall all around
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
四月的小雨  奏出美妙的旋律
-Little April shower -With your beautiful sound
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
一滴一滴  奏出美妙的旋律
Beating a tune As you fall all around
滴滴答答  四月的小雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
奏出世上最美妙的旋律
What can compare With your beautiful sound?
美妙的旋律  美妙的旋律
Beautiful sound
妈妈，我们今天要做什么？
Mother, what we going to do today?
我要带你到草地上去
I'm going to take you to the meadow.
草地？ 草地是什么呀？
Meadow? What's the meadow?
草地呀，是一个很好玩的地方
It's a very wonderful place.
那为什么我们以前都没去呢？
Then why haven't we been there before?
因为那个时候你年纪还小啊
You weren't big enough.
妈妈，你知道为什么吗？
Mother, you know what?
什么？
What?
我们不是在这里唯一的鹿
We're not the only deer in the forest.
你从哪儿听来的？
Where did you hear that?
是桑普告诉我的
Thumper told me.
它说的没错！
Well, he's right.
除了我们之外 森林里面还有很多的鹿
There are many deer in the forest besides us.
那为什么我们 都没有看到它们呢？
Then why don't I ever see them?
总有一天你会见到的
You will, sometime.
在草地上
On the meadow?
说不定
Perhaps.
我们就快要到了
We're almost there.
- 草地！  - 等等
-The meadow. -Wait.
斑比  等下
Bambi, wait.
千万不可以在草地上乱跑
You must never rush out on the meadow.
这样会有危险的
There might be danger.
在草地上我们得不到保护
Out there, we're unprotected.
草地非常的宽广
The meadow is wide and open,
没有树，还有丛森来隐藏
and there are no trees or bushes to hide us.
所以我们要非常的小心
So we have to be very careful.
你在这里等我
Wait here.
我先走出去
I'll go out first.
假如草地很安全我就通知你
And if the meadow is safe, I'll call you.
斑比，可以出来了
Come on, Bambi.
不要怕啊
It's all right.
快出来啊
Come on.
早啊，斑比王子
Good morning, Prince Bambi.
早，小王子！
Good morning, young prince.
你好，你们在吃什么啊？
Hello. What ya eatin'?
苜蓿！
Clover.
很像很好吃喔！
It's awfully good.
美味可口喔！
It's delicious.
你也吃吃看吧？
Why don't you try some?
不对！不对，不是吃叶子
No, not that green stuff.
只吃花果
Just eat the blossoms.
它是最美味的东西
That's the good stuff.
桑普！
Thumper.
什么事，妈妈？
Yes, Mama?
你爸爸是怎么告诉你的？
What did your father tell you?
有关于什么？
About what?
关于吃花果不吃绿叶的事啊
About eating the blossoms and leaving the greens?
原来是那个啊
Oh, that one.
吃绿叶对长身体有好处
Eating greens is a special treat.
会长出长耳朵和大脚
It makes long ears and great big feet.
不过绿叶的味道真的很难吃
But it sure is awful stuff to eat.
最后一句话是我自己编的
I made that last part up myself.
小心喔，小心…
Watch out.
她是小芬妮
That's little Faline.
妈妈，它会不好意思喔
He's kind of bashful, isn't he, Mama?
如果你跟他打声招呼就不会了
Well, maybe he wouldn't be if you'd say hello.
你好，斑比！
Hello, Bambi.
你好啊！
I said hello.
斑比，赶快回答她啊！
Well, aren't you going to answer her?
你应该不会害怕，对不对？
You're not afraid, are you?
赶快上前去啊
Well, then, go ahead.
快说啊，快说你好！
Go on, say hello.
你好！
Hello.
他停下来看着我
He stopped and looked at me.
是啊，我知道
Yes, I know.
为什么它在草地上出现
Why was everyone still
大家都不动呢？
when he came on the meadow?
因为大家都很尊敬他
Everyone respects him.
森林里所有的鹿 没有一只活得比他还要长久的
For of all the deer in the forest, not one has lived half so long.
他既勇敢，又很贤能
He's very brave and very wise.
所以他是大家公认的森林大王子
That's why he's known as the Great Prince of the Forest.
芬妮！
Faline.
斑比
Bambi.
妈妈！
Mother.
斑比…
Bambi.
妈…
Mother.
斑比，可以出来了
Come on out, Bambi.
现在已经很安全了
It's safe now.
已经不必躲藏了
We don't have to hide any longer.
妈妈 到底发生什么事了？ 为什么我们要跑呢？
What happened, Mother? Why did we all run?
这是因为人类来到了森林
Man was in the forest.
妈，快看  外面那是什么？
Mother, look. What's all that white stuff?
啊，那是雪
Why, it's snow.
雪？
Snow?
对啊，因为冬天已经来了
Yes. Winter has come.
你好啊，斑比！
Hiya, Bambi.
过来这边，看看我的能耐！
Watch what I can do.
过来，没关系嘛！
Come on. It's all right.
你看！
Look.
它已经凝固了
The water's stiff.
好好玩！ 对不对，斑比？
Some fun, huh, Bambi?
起来嘛！像我这个样子
Come on, get up. Like this.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
你会摇摇晃晃的，对不对呀？
Kinda wobbly, aren't you?
你不能光看前脚 也要注意后脚嘛！
Got to watch both ends at the same time.
我想你的脚不打结会比较好看
Guess you better unwind it.
起床！起床了！
Wake up.
该起床了！ 小花
Wake up, Flower.
春天到了吗？
Is it spring yet?
没有，冬天才刚开始呢！
No. Winter's just started.
你在做什么啊？
What you doing?
你在冬眠吗？
Hibernating?
那你为什么要冬眠呢？
What do you want to do that for?
就是我可以长时间的睡觉嘛！
All us flowers sleep in the winter.
晚安了，两位！
Well, good night.
冬天很漫长是不是，妈妈？
Winter sure is long, isn't it?
感觉上很漫长
It seems long.
可是它不会永远持续下去的
But it won't last forever.
我肚子饿死了
I'm awful hungry, Mother.
我知道，忍耐一下吧！
Yes, I know.
斑比…过来呀！
Bambi, come here.
你看！
Look.
这是春天的嫩草喔！
New spring grass.
斑比，快跑！
Bambi. Quick.
躲到草丛里！
The thicket.
快  快跑  斑比
Faster. Faster, Bambi.
别往后看！不停的跑！
Don't look back. Keep running.
快跑啊！
Keep running.
我们成功了！
We made it.
我们跑回来了，妈妈！
We made it, Mother.
我们…
We...
妈…
Mother.
妈妈…！
Mother!
妈妈… 你在哪
Mother, where are you?
妈妈…
Mother!
妈…
你妈妈再也不能陪在你身边了
Your mother can't be with you anymore.
跟我来！
Come.
我的孩子！
My son.
让我们唱一首春之颂
Let's sing a gay little spring song
这是值得欢唱的季节
This is the season to sing
我建议大家高声歌唱
So I'd like to suggest That we all do our best
唱一首春之颂
And warble a song about spring
春天…  春天…
Spring, spring, spring
让我们齐声歌唱
Let's get together and sing
让我们唱一首春之颂
Let's sing a gay little spring song
就像展翅高飞的鸟儿
Just like the bird on the wing
当你心情愉快一切都很美好
Things always seem right When you're cheerful and bright
让我们齐声歌唱
So let's get together and sing
歌唱…  歌唱…
Sing, sing, sing
让我们唱一首春之颂
Let's sing a song about spring
让我们像五月天的鸟儿吱吱喳喳地歌唱
Let's twitter and tweet Like the birdies in May
把握机会  及时享乐
Get into the mood And be merry today
忘掉忧愁  高声欢唱
Forget all your troubles And warble away...
怎么了 ？
Wait.
又怎么了 ？
What now?
嘿！
Hey.
不要吵
Stop that racket.
走开！
Scat.
让我们唱一首春之颂
Let's sing a song about spring
我要来修理他们
I'll fix 'em.
好了，它们得到教训了！
There. I guess that'll teach 'em.
没用啊！
Oh, what's the use?
这是值得欢唱的季节
This is the season to sing...
每年春天都在唱情歌
Same thing every spring.
甜蜜的情歌
Love's sweet song.
真受不了，这些个家伙
Pain in the pin feathers, I call it.
别摇了
Stop it.
你们快滚开！
Get out of here. All of you.
你是谁啊你…
And you, too.
你好啊，猫头鹰朋友
Hello, Friend Owl.
你还记得我吗？
Don't you remember me?
原来是小王子啊
Why, it's the young prince.
斑比
Bambi!
我的天啦，你长得都变了
My, my, how you've changed.
来…转过来让我看看
Turn round there. Let me look at you.
我猜呀…你是以你的斑
I see you've traded in your spots
来换取一对鹿角，对不对啊？
for a pair of antlers.
你知道吗？
You know,
前天啊…我还自己在想呢
just the other day
我们不知道你变成什么样子了
I was talking to myself about you.
而且我好想你喔！
And we were wondering what had become of you.
你好，斑比！
Hello, Bambi.
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
桑普！
Thumper.
答对了！
Right.
各位！
Hi, fellas.
小花！
Flower.
对喔！
Yeah.
他们是怎么搞的？
Well, what's the matter with them?
怎么会有那种动作，好奇怪喔
Why are they acting that way?
你们不知道吗？
Why, don't you know?
他们恋爱了
They're "twitterpated."
恋爱…
Twitterpated?
没错，到了春天了
Yes. Nearly everybody
大家都这样的
gets twitterpated in the spring time.
比如说
For example,
你一个人走着在想心事
you're walking along, minding your own business,
你既不看左呢…也不看右
you're looking neither to the left nor to the right,
突然间，你撞见一个漂亮的脸孔
when all of a sudden you run smack into a pretty face.
然后…头昏眼花的
Your head's in a whirl.
你就感觉魂飞出去一样…
轻飘飘的
还没弄清楚呢！
And before you know it,
原来你是在空中漫步
you're walking on air.
然后呢…你知道结果怎么样了？
And then you know what?
你会在空中，像这样的旋转
You're knocked for a loop.
整天的失去理智了  就像这样
And you completely lose your head.
真可怕
Gosh, that's awful.
就是嘛！
-Gee whiz. -Terrible.
不光是这样
And that ain't all.
任何的动物都会碰上的
It can happen to anybody.
劝你们要小心一点喔！
So you'd better be careful.
会让你们碰上的
It could happen to you,
还有你！
and you,
还有你
and...
你也会碰上的
Yes, it could even happen to you.
不会发生在我身上，我敢保证
Well, it's not going to happen to me.
我也不?
Me neither.
哼！恋爱
Twitterpated.
你好啊！
Hello.
斑比，你好啊！
Hello, Bambi.
你还记不记得我呢？
Don't you remember me?
我是芬妮啊！
I'm Faline.
斑比！
Bambi.
斑比
我为你带来一首歌
I bring you a song
我要对着你高歌
And I sing as I go
因为我要你知道
For I want you to know
我在寻找爱情
That I'm looking for romance
我为你带来一首歌
I bring you a song
我希望你知道
In the hope that you'll see
当你看着我
When you're looking at me
我在寻找爱情
That I'm looking for love
我要寻找爱情的光辉
I'm seeking that glow
趁我们还年轻  就在五月天
Only found when you're young and it's May
在那美好的一天
Only found on that wonderful day
对爱情的渴望已满足
When all longing is through
我要寻找爱情的光辉
I'm seeking that glow
当我俩心意相通
Only found when a thrill is complete
两颗心紧紧地结合
Only found when two hearts gently beat
就会随着美妙音乐起舞  心情顿时焕然一新
To the strains of a waltz That's both tender and new
我为你带来一首歌
I bring you a song
因为我在寻找爱情
For I'm seeking romance
当你在我身边  就连天上的月亮
You're by my side There's a moon up above
都散发出耀眼却温柔的光芒
It shines with a light That's so mellow and bright
大家都看得出来  今晚我们将坠入爱河
It's easy to see That tonight we shall fall in love
我为你带来一首歌
I bring you a song
因为我在寻找爱情
For I'm seeking romance
也在寻找你
And you
是人类！
It is Man.
他们又来到这里了
He is here again.
在这个时候 会有很多的人类来这里
There are many this time.
所以我们要躲入森林里面
We must go deep into the forest.
快点！斑比，跟我走！
Hurry. Follow me.
芬妮
Faline.
斑比！
Bambi.
斑比，你在哪里？
Bambi, where are you?
斑比…
Bambi.
芬妮…
Faline.
你听！
Listen.
他来了！
He's coming.
嘘
Hush.
安静
Be quiet.
他靠近了
He's coming closer.
冷静  别紧张啊
Be calm. Don't get excited.
我们还是飞走好了！
We better fly.
不行，不能飞啊！
No. No, don't fly.
不管怎么样，都不能飞呀！
Whatever you do, don't fly.
他就快到了！
He's almost here.
我受不了了
I can't stand it any longer.
斑比…
Bambi.
芬妮
Faline.
斑比…
Bambi!
芬妮，快走
Quick, Faline. Jump.
站起来，斑比！
Get up, Bambi.
站起来！
Get up.
你一定要站起来！
You must get up.
起来！
Get up.
快站起来！
跟我走！
Now, come with me.
斑比！
Bambi.
起床！起床哦！猫头鹰
Wake up. Wake up, Friend Owl.
起床哦！
Wake up, Friend Owl.
发…发生什么事了 ？
What now?
到底怎么回事啊？
Hey, what's going on around here?
- 发生了！  - 发生什么了？
-It's happened. -Happened?
对喔，在草丛里面！斑比，快点
Yes. In the thicket. Hurry up, Bambi.
是的，爸爸！我来了
Yes, Papa. I'm coming.
你们看！
Look.
有两只呢！好可爱喔！
Two of them.
我还真不敢相信哪！
Well, I don't believe
他们两个长得好像小斑比
I've ever seen a more likely looking pair of fawns.
斑比王子一定感到无限的骄傲
Prince Bambi ought to be mighty proud.
爱是一首
Love is a song
永不止息的诗歌
That never ends
一个简单的主题
One simple theme
不停回响
Repeating
就像是
Like the voice
天堂传来的歌声
Of a heavenly choir
爱的美妙乐章
Love's sweet music
永远流传
Flows on